啦啦队队长:走,姑娘们.走,杜威喇叭们.胜利胜利,胜利属于我们,走----喇叭们!
Cheerleaders: Go Girls.Go you Dewey Hooters.V V victory for var var varsity.Victory
for varsity, goooooo Hooters
扩音器:迈克*希佛,请到校长办公室.
Loudspeaker: Mike Seaver to the principles office.
迈克*希佛,请马上到校长办公室.
Mike Seaver come to the principles office immediately, Mr.
女孩1:我是说,一个人可以很可爱,
Girl a: Well I mean, its like a scientific fact that you can be cute,
或者很深沉;但是如果他既可爱又深沉,只有百万分之一的机会.我觉得这是一个客观事实.
or you can be deep, but only one in a million can be cute and deep.
女孩2:对.就像去年夏天的时候,
Girl b: Yeah.It's like last summer I thought I might try being really
我觉得我今年会真的变得更深沉一点,但是……
deep this year, but....
女孩1:那,你会怎么形容开萝尔*希佛那样类型的人?
Girl a: Ok.So then, um, what would you call someone like Carol Seaver?
女孩2:可怜的书虫.
Girl b: Pathetic.
迈克:喂,开萝尔.
Mike: Ah, look Carol.I need you to write me a note, to the principles office.
我需要你的帮助,帮我写个便条给校长办公室,要模仿妈妈的笔迹.
In mum's handwriting.
开萝尔:这次你又想干什么?
Carol: What you do this time?
迈克:我还不知道呢.
Mike: I don't know yet,
嗨,汤姆.
so why don't you make it one of those all purpose deals, ok.Hey Tom.
还好么?
How are you doing.
开萝尔:站住.
Carol: Stand still.
开萝尔:你以为你是谁啊傻子?你是我妹妹.
Mike: What are you nuts?You're my sister.You're a book head.
你是个书虫.你吃中饭的时候还学习.
You even study during lunch.
扩音器:上一次的公示取消.开萝尔*希佛,
Loudspeaker: Scrap that last announcement.
请到校长办公室.这次是开萝尔*希佛.
Carol Seaver come to the principles office.Please.That's Carol Seaver.
迈克:好.
Mike: Alright.
扩音器:十分抱歉,迈克.刚才的错误不是有意的.
Loudspeaker: Sorry Mike.It was an honest mistake.
迈克:嗨,没关系.
Mike: Hey , no sweat.
开萝尔:妈妈还没回家么?
Carol: is mum home yet?
本:没.
Ben: No.
开萝尔:爸爸呢?
Carol: Dad?
本:在家,和一个病人在一起,不过我可以先跟他说一声.
Ben: In with a patient, but I get to talk with him first.
开萝尔:那么还是跟妈妈说吧.本!
Carol: Ah well, I want to talk to mum anyway.Ben!
你不应该暴饮暴食.
You know you are not supposed to be pigging out like that.
本:不是为了我,是为了迈克.
Ben: Yeah, well, it's not for me.It's for Mike.
迈克:嗨,谢谢你本儿.
Mike: Hey thanks Bennie.
迈克:开萝尔,校长是不是要以你的名字给学校取名儿啊?"
Mike: So, Carol.Did the principle decide to name the school after you?
呆子高中".
Nerd High.
开萝尔:事实上,
Carol: well, as a matter of fact,
他叫我去是问我是否愿意跳级.
he called me in to say if I wanted to, I could skip a grade.
迈克:呵.哦哦哦,开萝尔.如果你跳一级,那不是说我们俩会一起升入第11年级.
Mike: whoopee.Wo wo wo Carol.If you skip a year, then that means that
we are both going to be in the eleventh grade, together
开萝尔:只一年,之后我会升到第12年级,
Carol: Well, only for a year, and then I'll move on to twelfth grade,
你呢就可以再次完全拥有第11年级了.
and you can have eleventh all to yourself again.
迈克:嘿!
Mike: Hey!
迈克:开萝尔跟我同年级.真让人难受.
Mike: Carol in my grade.This really sucks eggs.
本:嗨,迈克.这是杰伊.
Ben: Hey mike.It's jerry.
迈克:杰伊,我现在没时间聊.
Mike: Look jerry.I can't talk now.I just got the worst news.
我刚得到个坏消息.你现在没法让我开心.她真是优秀的不可思议.
No nothing you can say can cheer me up right now.Oh yeah.
你是认真的么?哇.我不知道,
How incredibly gorgeous is she.Are you serious?Oh wow.I don't know man.
伙计.那是个晚自习.
It's a school night.She's a stewardess!Oh really.No no no no.
她是个空姐!哦,
I'm in on it.Just let me run it by my dad.
真的么.不不不不,我感兴趣.
It makes him feel involved.
杰森:本戴尔先生,我们下一个疗程中,
Jason: Well Mr Bendelle, for our next session,
我希望你想一想为什么你遇到了这么多的困难.
I'd like you to think about why it is you have so much difficulty just
好了,我们下周见.
talking to people.Well, ok then.I'll see you next week.
迈克:嗨,爸爸!
Mike: Hey dad!
本:爸爸!
Ben: Dad!
开萝尔:妈妈,那是妈妈么?
Carol: Mum, is that mum?
迈克:爸爸,我今晚可以出去么?
Mike: Dad, can I go out tonight?
本:我先到这儿的.
Ben: I was here first.
迈克:先到的是我.
Mike: I was
本:迈克!
Ben: Mike!
迈克:本!
Mike: Ben!
杰森:孩子们!
Jason: Boys!
开萝尔:妈妈!
Carol: Mum!
杰森:她还没到家.
Jason: She's not home.
麦琪:麦琪:杰森,我回来了.
Maggie: Jason, I'm home.
杰森:开萝尔!
Jason: Ok.Carol!
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
迈克:妈妈!
Mike: Mum!
麦琪:迈克!
Maggie: Mike!
迈克:不,开萝尔.
Mike: No Carol.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
杰森:停!本,什么事?
Jason: Stop!Ben, what?
本:我想在邻居家玩.
Ben: I want to play next door.
杰森:好的.开萝尔?
Jason: Fine.Carol?
开萝尔:我有话要和妈妈说.
Carol: I want to talk to mum.
杰森:好.迈克?
Jason: Fine.Mike?
迈克:我今晚想出去.
Mike: I want to go out tonight.
杰森:今晚要上学的.
Jason: It's a school night.
迈克:这回怎么不"好"了?
Mike: What happened to fine?
麦琪:开萝尔,你想说什么?
Maggie: So Carol, what do you need to talk about?
开萝尔:校长今天没跟你打电话么?
Carol: Well, did the principle call you today?
麦琪:没!现在迈克做得怎么样?
Maggie: Oh no!What did Mike do now?
开萝尔:没事.是我.我想先告诉您.
Carol: Nothing.It's me.I wanted to tell you first.
杰森:对不起,如果不告诉我,你们俩也别想继续谈.
Jason: Sorry, you're just not going anywhere until I have some details.
迈克:好吧,爸爸.男人对男人,
Mike: Yeah, alright dad.Man to man, the truth.
以诚相待.我已经答应人家出去,初次见面,挺小,
I have agreed to go out on a blind date with this shy young fragile girl
挺羞涩,挺柔弱的一个女孩,她只在城里呆一个晚上.
who is only in town for one night.
杰森:出来旅游的女高中生?
Jason: A traveling high school girl?
迈克:对,交流项目学生.
Mike: Exchange student, yeah.
杰森:不!
Jason: No!
迈克:如果妈妈同意,那你会同意么?
Mike: Well, if it's ok with mum, is it ok with you?
杰森:那,祝你好运了!
Jason: yeah, good luck!
麦琪:满分.真是我的女儿.开萝尔,这真是太出色了.
Maggie: A whole grade.That's my girl.Carol this is absolutely fabulous.
杰森:什么事?什么太出色了?
Jason: What?What's fabulous?
麦琪:哦,开萝尔,你爸爸还没知道?
Maggie: Oh Carol, your father doesn't know?
开萝尔:让校长电话里告诉他吧.
Carol: Well not unless the principle called him.
杰森:你现在在做什么?
Jason: What did you do now?
迈克:没事.校长办公室叫的是开萝尔.
Mike: Nothing.Carol's the one who got sent to the principles office.
杰森:开萝尔,宝贝.怎么回事?
Jason: Carol honey.What's the matter?
迈克:开萝尔,宝贝!对不起,这出了个大岔子.
Mike: Carol.Honey!Sorry, there is something very wrong.
麦琪:开萝尔快跳级了.
Maggie: Carol's going to skip a grade.
开萝尔:我得先通过10年级的考试,不过……
Carol: Well, I have to pass a tenth grade proficiency test, of course, but...
杰森:好.
Jason: Well, that's nice.
麦琪:杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
杰森:非常好.
Jason: It's very nice.
麦琪:宝贝.你爸爸其实非常高兴.
Maggie: Honey, he's thrilled.
迈克:妈妈,听我说,很快的,爸爸说如果您同意我就今晚可以出去.
Mike: Ah mum.Just listen real quick.Dad says I can go out tonight if it's alright with you.
麦琪:同意.
Maggie: Ok.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
麦琪:好么?
Maggie: Nice?
杰森:我说过了,非常好.
Jason: I said very nice.
麦琪:我不明白你什么意思,杰森.
Maggie: I don't understand you Jason.
跳一级是相当大的成就.
Skipping an entire grade is a real achievement.
杰森:可能是,但是最近有一些研究表明青春期的少男少女……
Jason: Well it can be, but there are some recent studies that adolescents...
麦琪:我不想让她听那些关于青春期少男少女的近期研究.是开萝尔,我们的女儿,
Maggie: I don't want to hear about recent studies of adolescents.
她不一样的.她有目标,有抱负.
I mean this is Carol.Our daughter.She's different.She has goals, ambitions.
杰森:就像她母亲?
Jason: Like her mother?
麦琪:一点儿没错.难道有错么?
Maggie: Exactly.Something wrong with that?
杰森:你说过你不想知道那些研究.
Jason: You said you didn't want to hear about it.
麦琪:我刚才没有准备好.现在好了.
Maggie: Well I wasn't ready then.I am now.
杰森:好的.问题是,
Jason: Ok.Well the question is, not whether she should skip the tenth grade,
不是她是否应该跳级,而是为什么她愿意跳级.是因为你想让她这么做?
but why she wants to.Is it because you want her to?
还是因为有了额外的学习任务她就可以不参加学校的活动了?可能她参加这些活动觉得很别扭,
Is it because with the additional work load,
有障碍.如果是这样,跳级后,
she won't have time for the social activities she's not too comfortable
和大一岁的孩子们在一起,她难道不会觉得更别扭,
with anyway?And won't she be even more uncomfortable with kids who are
更不能适应么?而且,如果跳级后,
a year more mature?And what if she fails?
她成绩不好怎么办?她真的对此类的压力有所准备么?
Is she really ready for that kind of pressure?
麦琪:你知不知道和一个什么时候都很理智的人结婚会多压抑?
Maggie: Do you have any idea how frustrating it is to be married to someone
who's always so rational?
杰森:一点儿都不知道.
Jason: Not a clue.
迈克:对不起.我只是想表述一下我对开萝尔跳级的想法.
Mike: Excuse me.I would just like to express my thoughts on Carol skipping
作为哥哥,我对妹妹不能不管,
this grade.As an older brother who cares for, no no, I'll just say it;
不不,我是说,
who loves his younger sister, I just like to say....
我对妹妹很关心,
please don't let Carol skip this grade.I don't ask much from you guys.
我的意思是……不要让开萝尔跳这级了.我从前没要过你们什么东西,
Just a little allowance and some shelter from the rain.
不过是一些零花钱和一个遮风挡雨的住的地方,有时候几个汉堡而已.
The odd burger now and then.
麦琪:直说,迈克.
Maggie: Get up Mike.
迈克:我不是为了我自己.绝对不是.
Mike: No, I'm not asking for myself.No.
就个人而言,我会觉得很高兴能和开萝尔在一个课堂共同进步.
Personally I would find having Carol in the class a delightful experience.
我是为了大家,代表的是整个第十一年级.
I'm asking on behalf of the entire eleventh grade.
杰森:这有什么问题么?
Jason: And what's there problem?
迈克:基本上来说,他们觉得和开萝尔在一起,
Mike: Well basically, they feel that with Carol in the class,
我们班的书虫比例就会超标.
we will have exceeded our nerd quota.
杰森:哦,真的么.
Jason: Oh really.
迈克:对,爸爸.知道为什么.有一个非常微妙的平衡.
Mike: Yeah dad.You know how it is.It's a very delicate balance.
再多一个书虫,天平就会倾斜.然后,混乱.
One more nerd tips.Chaos.
迈克:宝贝,晚饭马上就好了.
Maggie: Honey, dinner will be ready in just a minute.
开萝尔:不.我没胃口.我正在学习呢.
Carol: No.I lost my appetite mum.I'm studying about the Donna party.
麦琪:哦,听着,开萝尔.只是一个很短的问题.
Maggie: Oh listen Carol.Just one quick question.
开萝尔:讲.
Carol: Sure.
麦琪:跳级的事儿,
Maggie: This business of skipping a grade,
是你自己愿意的么?
you would be doing it for yourself right?
开萝尔:当然.
Carol: Of course.
麦琪:好.不是为了把头埋在书堆里,逃避一年的社会活动,不和其它孩子交往,是么?
Maggie: Ok.And it isn't to avoid a years worth of social activity and keeping
your nose buried in books instead of interacting with other kids?Is it
开萝尔:不是.
Carol: No.
麦琪:太好了.至于额外的压力,你已经想过了?
Maggie: Great.And you've thought about the additional pressures, right?
开萝尔:什么压力?
Carol: What pressures?
麦琪:什么压力!真是我闺女.
Maggie: What pressures!That's my girl.
本:我只是好奇,对其它人来说这也是错的么?
Ben: I'm just curious.Does this seem wrong to anyone else?
杰森:迈克,帮你弟弟洗洗碗.
Jason: Mike, help your brother with the dishes please.
迈克:没问题.本,洗碗机在那边.
Mike: Sure.Ben the dishwasher is just that way.
开萝尔:如果谈话已经结束那我要学习了.
Carol: So, if we've finished talking about this, I have to go study.
麦琪:我完事了,杰森.
Maggie: I'm finished Jason.
杰森:加油,开萝尔.
Jason: Go ahead Carol.
麦琪:明白我意思么.她已经对此完全考虑再三了.
Maggie: See what I mean.She's thought this completely through.
真不明白你为什么弄得我这么的忧心忡忡.
I don't know why I let you get me so worried about it.
杰森:我只是禁不住有些疑虑.
Jason: Well, I just can't help but wondering..
麦琪:如果我要是留了一级,对我来说事情可能大不一样.
Maggie: Boy, if I'd have had that extra year,
我会到68年才毕业了,74年生本,84年回来上班.
things would have been a lot different for me.I would have graduated in 68.
不,等会儿.
Had Ben in 74.Got back to work in 84.Why, I'd be a year younger.No wait.
杰森:开萝尔,如果你跳一级,你会想念自己的朋友么?
Jason: Carol, if you skip a grade, wont you miss your friends?
开萝尔:只是跳级,并不要换学校,爸爸.
Carol: Well, it's not like I'm going to be changing schools dad.
本:我觉得她应该跳级.这是个机会,
Ben: I think she should skip the grade.
可以把迈克整个这一年都搞砸.
It's a chance to mess up Mike's whole year.
开萝尔:我的生活很好.
Carol: My life is good.
杰森:我确实很欣赏你的决心,而且你使我想起了你的妈妈.
Jason: Well I do admire you determination.And you remind me of your mum.
开萝尔:不过,她犯过的错误我不会再犯,
Carol: Yeah, but I won't make the same mistake she did.
婚姻,家庭这一方面.
With the marriage and family bit.
麦琪:她说的?
Maggie: Did she just say?
杰森:对.
Jason: Yeah, she did.
麦琪:婚姻和家庭是个错误.她是从哪儿有这儿想法的?
Maggie: Marriage and family are a mistake.Where would she get such an idea?
杰森:哦,亲爱的.不要自责.
Jason: Oh honey.Don't blame yourself.
麦琪:我?我么?你是说,是我让她有了那样的想法?
Maggie: Me?Me?You're suggesting that I gave her that idea?
杰森:不不不.
Jason: No.No no.
麦琪:我是说我愿意嫁给你,
Maggie: I mean I love being married to you.I love my family.
珍爱这个家.
I mean there's time when I think about it when I was gush.
杰森:我知道.
Jason: I know that.I've seen you gush.
麦琪:那她会是从哪儿得到这样一个想法呢?
Maggie: Then where would she get such an idea?
杰森:可能是从她仰慕的某些成年人那儿.
Jason: Well probably from some adults she admires.
麦琪:谁?
Maggie: Who?
杰森:我想会是和她亲近的某人.
Jason: I would guess someone close to her.
麦琪:女人.
Maggie: A woman.
杰森:对.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:哦,我明白了.现在,你又绕回来怪我是罪魁祸首.
Maggie: Oh I see.So now we're back to accusing me.
杰森:可能是她导致你做了错误的决定要重新回去工作.
Jason: Well maybe she's misread your decision to go back to work.
也许你确实有点过于看重出人头地了.
Maybe you do put a little too much emphasis on excelling.
麦琪:就好像以前训练.
Maggie: Just like potty training.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:为了妈妈!为了妈妈!为了妈妈!
Maggie: Do it for mommy!Do it for mommy!Do it for Mommy!
杰森:对不起,我得去趟洗手间.
Jason: Excuse me I have to go to the bathroom.
杰森:开萝尔,想不想和我出去看点冰琪淋,聊会儿跳级的事.好么?
Jason: Carol, why don't you and I go out for an ice cream cone, and we'll discuss skipping that grade.Ok?
开萝尔:冰琪淋会增肥的.
Carol: Ice cream is fattening.
杰森:你什么也不用担心.
Jason: You haven't got anything to worry about.
开萝尔:我没有考虑我自己.
Carol: I wasn't thinking about me.
(门铃)
(door bell)
杰森:门铃救了你的驾.
Jason: You were saved by the bell.
迈克:我搞定了,我搞定了,我搞定了.我一定要搞定她.
Mike: I got it.I got it.I got it.I'm going to get it!
凯蒂:嗨,我叫凯蒂,在航空公司工作.你一定是迈克喽.我这次是不是很幸运?我平常不出来和陌生人约会的.但是,我和男友分手了,就在十二天零半天前.她叫瑞科,而且之前也没有什么征兆,他把我给甩了.说我不成熟.
Kitty: Hi, I'm Kitty from bravo airlines.You must be Mike.Hey did I luck out this time or what?I mean I usually don't go out on blind dates, but I broke up with my boyfriend twelve and a half days ago.He name was Rico and with like no warning what so ever, he dumps me.Talk about immature.
杰森:对,你好.我是杰森*希佛.迈克的父亲.迈克!
Jason: Yeah, how do you do.I'm: Jason Seaver.I'm Mike's dad.Mike!
迈克:好.
Mike: Hi there.
杰森:凯蒂,对不起.迈克今晚不能和你出去.
Jason: Kitty I'm sorry.Mike can't go out with you tonight.
凯蒂:哦,为什么呢?他生病了?
Kitty: Oh why?Is he sick?
杰森:不,他太小.嗨,迈克.你为什么不带凯蒂带到外面走廊,你可以做进一步的解释?
Jason: No, he's young.Hey Mike.Why don't you take Kitty out on the porch and you can explain further.
迈克:我,我,不,爸爸.
Mike: I, I, no dad.
麦琪:杰森,这儿什么事?
Maggie: Jason.What's going on?
杰森:麦琪,这位是凯蒂.
Jason: Maggie, this is Kitty.
你同意迈克今晚出去见的就是她.
This is the woman you gave Mike permission to go out with tonight.
麦琪:我没同意.是你同意的.
Maggie: I didn't.You did.
迈克:啊,凯蒂.我有话说.
Mike: Ah Kitty.We must talk.
杰森:还得像平常那样惩罚你,否则你今晚就得高兴过头了?
Jason: Well the usual punishment, or are you feeling creative tonight?
麦琪:现在我头绪很乱,杰森.我得跟开萝尔谈谈.
Maggie: I can't think about it now Jason.I have to talk to Carol.
杰森:好.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:开萝尔,有时间么?
Maggie: Well Carol.Got a minute?
开萝尔:我一定得通过那考试.
Carol: I've just got to pass that proficiency test.
麦琪:我想说的就是……
Maggie: Well that's what I wanted to ..
开萝尔:知道么,我将提前一年读完高中,读完大学,将提前一年开始自己的事业,提前一年成为杂志的本年度最佳女性.
Carol: You know I'll finish high school a year earlier, I'll finish college a year earlier, start a business a year earlier, become Time magazines woman of the year a year earlier.
麦琪:那,在你退休之前,我想跟你说句话.
Maggie: Well, before you hit retirement, I'd like to have a word with you.
开萝尔:有什么不对么?
Carol: What's wrong?
麦琪:我不太肯定.可能是我反应过度,也可能是我听错了.你是不是说过一些不明智的东西,比如说婚姻和家庭是一种错误.
Maggie: I'm not sure.I mean I might be over reacting, and I probably heard you wrong.But I thought you said some silly thing about marriage and family being a mistake.
开萝尔:对
Carol: Right.
麦琪:对?
Maggie: Right?
开萝尔:对.
Carol: Yes.
麦琪:你是从哪儿学得?
Maggie: Where did you get an idea like that?
开萝尔:从你这儿.
Carol: From you.
麦琪:哦,宝贝.我根本不是这么想的.我的意思是说,我嫁给你爸爸因为我爱他,扶养你们长大因为我爱你们.你可以问任何人,只要是我们认识的.告诉我号码,我来打.
Maggie: Oh honey.You know that I don't feel that way at all.I mean I love being married to your dad.I love raising you kids.Ask anyone we know.Give me the phone, I'll dial.
开萝尔:妈妈,你为什么会变得这么激动?
Carol: Mum, why are you getting so excited?
麦琪:为什么?因为我有种感觉,
Maggie: Why?Because I get the feeling we haven't been talking about you
我们一直在讨论的不是你跳级的问题,而是你逃避生活的问题.
skipping a grade.We've been talking about you skipping life.
开萝尔:可是,从我记事开始,
Carol: But for as long as I can remember,
您告诉我的一直是努力工作,关注学业和事业.
you've told me to work hard and think about college and a career.
麦琪:哦,我是那么说的.
Maggie: Oh sure I did.
开萝尔:那,有了学业,事业,而后嫁人,
Carol: So what's the point of doing that just to get married,
前功尽弃,就像你本人做的那样,那还有什么意义?
and give it up like you did?
麦琪:我并没有舍弃什么东西.
Maggie: I haven't given up anything.
开萝尔:妈妈,你以前是在工作,为了扶养孩子所以才辞了.
Carol: Mum you worked for Newsweek and quit to raise kids.
麦琪:对,但是,但是现在我已经回去工作了.
Maggie: Well yes, but, but now I've gone back to work.
开萝尔:为一家地方报纸.
Carol: For a local newspaper.
麦琪:很有名,在西尔西斯排名第一,
Maggie: The Long Island Herald is number one in Siocit and number two
马萨皮卡排名第二.
in Massapequa.
开萝尔:一点儿没错.
Carol: Exactly.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的.这问题是有点复杂.错过了好时机,我也觉得非常遗憾;但是,结婚并且生育三个可爱的孩子,我一点也不觉得遗憾.你明白么?
Maggie: Oh honey.I know this is a little bit complicated, I mean sure I'm
sorry that I missed the big time, but I'm not sorry at all about getting
married and having three great kids.Do you understand
开萝尔:明白.
Carol: Yes.
麦琪:真的明白?
Maggie: Are you sure?
开萝尔:当然.你觉得自己必须这么说,不这么说又能说些什么呢?因为你有些事情你不得不去做,你感到后悔.
Carol: Of course.You think you have to say this because you regret what you had to do.
麦琪:哦,不不.我不后悔.
Maggie: Oh no no, I don't.
开萝尔:你肯定后悔.
Carol: Of course you do.And don't worry about it.
不必担心.因为我会让您为我而自豪的,
Because I am going to make you so proud of me that you are going to
你会为我而疯狂.
go crazy.
麦琪:我已经实现了自己的目标,没有遗憾.
Maggie: I'm already there.
迈克:你知道,凯蒂,我以前是比这个大许多.
Mike: So you see Kitty, I used to be much older than this.
凯蒂:哦,亲爱的!
Kitty: Oh dear!
迈克:那病真的是极为罕见.
Mike: It's an extremely rare disease.
凯蒂:那真的太有趣了.
Kitty: That is really amazing.
迈克:哦,不,非常的惨痛.
Mike: Oh and tragic too.
凯蒂:我觉得也是.
Kitty: I would think so.
迈克:就我所知,我是这世界上已知的仅有的两例之一.一个是我,另一个是,呃,迪克*克拉克.
Mike: I mean I was, as far as I know there are only two reported
cases in the world.Me and uh, Dick Clark
凯蒂:但是,你并不有表现出什么痛苦.
Kitty: But you don't show your pain.
迈克:是的,我没表现出什么.
Mike: No, no I don't.
我的意思是,处在青春期这个阶段会是什么样子,你了解么?
I mean do you have any idea what it's like going through puberty backwards?
凯蒂:我可以想像的到.如果有人找到了这病的疗方,那就给我打个电话.
Kitty: I can imagine.If they ever find a cure for this, give me a call.
迈克:一定会的.(她吻他)我已经看到未来了,
Mike: You can count on it.(she kisses him) I have seen the future.
是美好的未来!
And it is good!
麦琪:杰森,帮我个忙.会很快很干净的.
Maggie: Jason, do me a favor.Shoot me.It will be quick and clean.
我们可以在前面草坪上做,打开洒水器,一点儿都不乱.
We can do it on the front lawn, turn on the sprinklers, no mess at all.
杰森:一切都很好.
Jason: So it went well.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,这都是我的错.
Maggie: Oh honey, this is all my fault.And do you know why?
你知道为什么么?你肯定知道.你无所不知.
Of course you know why.You know everything.
杰森:那是我的……
Jason: Well, it's my....
麦琪:她觉得我有点像圣徒,
Maggie: She thinks I'm some kind of a saint who gave up everything for
为了你和孩子们放弃了一切.
you and the kids.
杰森:她知道那是你自己的选择么?
Jason: Does she know that's the choice you made?
麦琪:知道.但是她不相信我.
Maggie: Yes.And she didn't believe me.
我真希望她对自己出生之前的事真的有所了解.
Oh I wish she'd been around before she was born.
杰森:可能那办法还真可行.
Jason: You know that might work.
麦琪:在我说话站不住脚的时候不要取笑我.哦,亲爱的,
Maggie: Don't humor me when I don't make any sense.
如果你有什么主意,我想听一听.我以前不这么想.
Oh honey if you have any ideas, I'd love to hear them.I didn't think so.
开萝尔:爸爸,你没睡,还在做什么?
Carol: Dad, what are you still doing awake?
杰森:我这儿有些东西,你或许会感兴趣.
Jason: Well, I just have something here I think you might be interested in.
开萝尔:不会又是一首盖瑞的歌吧?
Carol: Not another song by Gary Pucket and the Union Gap?
杰森:不,你为什么会那么说?
Jason: No, why do you say that?
开萝尔:因为每次拿那个老录音机出来的时候,
Carol: Because every time you get out the old tape recorder,
总是会放一些很恐怖的老歌.
it's to play some terrible old song.
杰森:不过盖瑞是位有才华的艺术家.
Jason: Well Gary Pucket happens to be an artist.
And that's not what this is about.
开萝尔:我还有很多功课要做,爸爸.
Carol: I still have a lot of studying to do dad.
杰森:只要你有机会听的时候,你就听.倾听.
Jason: Well just listen when you have a chance.Listen.
这是冲击波,来自过去.1971.
It's a blast from the past.1971.
开萝尔:这是盖瑞(放进磁带)
Carol: It is Gary Pucket.(puts tape on)
磁带:(沉重的呼吸)
Tape: (heavy breathing)
医生:您挡着道儿了,希佛先生.
Doctor: You're in the way Mr Seaver.
杰森:我就是医生.
Jason: I'm a doctor.
医生:我也是医生,你还是没让道儿.
Doctor: So am I and you're still in the way.
杰森:来,亲爱的.用力,再来一下.
Jason: Come on honey.One more push.
麦琪:我还要去其它什么地方?
Maggie: Sure, where else am I going to go.
杰森:来,一,二,三,用力.
Jason: Come on.One, two, three and push!
麦琪:喔-----!
Maggie: Ooooh!
医生:出来了.
Doctor: Here it comes.
杰森:我看到她了,麦琪.
Jason: I see him Maggie.Just a little more.
麦琪:啊------!
Maggie: Ahhhhhh!
(婴儿的哭泣声)
(sound of baby crying)
杰森:哇.快看她.女孩.
Jason: Wow.Just look at him.Her.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的.
Maggie: Oh honey
杰森:女孩,是个女孩!
Jason: Her.It's a her!
麦琪:我们有了一个女孩!
Maggie: We have a daughter!
杰森:你好,亚历克西斯.
Jason: Hello Alexis.
麦琪:不是亚历克西斯.
Maggie: Not Alexis.
杰森:但是我们商量过的……
Jason: But we agreed on ...
麦琪:但是,那时候我以为要生的是个男孩.
Maggie: But that's when I thought it would be a boy.
杰森:护士,啊,我们……
Jason: Nurse, well ah, we...
麦琪:哦,她多漂亮啊,是吧,
Maggie: Oh isn't she beautiful Jason?I don't care what we call it.
杰森?我们叫她什么我都不会在意.这是我一生中最幸福的一天.
This is the happiest day of my life.
杰森:她像我.
Jason: She looks like you.
麦琪:准备送她到哪儿上大学?
Maggie: Where is she going to go to college?
杰森:在我们决定她的大学之前,我们是不是先给她起个名字?
Jason: Before we decide on a college, shouldn't we give her a name?
麦琪:好吧,杰森,开萝尔不愿意上大学.
Maggie: Well Jason, maybe Carol won't go to college.
杰森:开萝尔?
Jason: Carol?
麦琪:我一直都很喜欢这个名字.你呢?
Maggie: I've always liked that name.Do you?
杰森:呃……
Jason: Well, uh...
麦琪:哦,她做什么我都不会在乎的,
Maggie: Oh I don't care what she wants to do,
只要她会和现在一样幸福.
just as long as she's as happy as I am right now.
杰森:开萝尔,就叫这名字.
Jason: Carol it is then.
麦琪:哦,杰森,我爱你.
Maggie: Oh Jason, I love you.
(婴儿哭)
(Baby crying)
麦琪:那听起来像是一个女人后悔自己的选择么?
Maggie: Does that sound like a woman who regretted her choice?
开萝尔:我一直以为……
Carol: I always thought...
麦琪:哦天哦天哦天,你错了么?
Maggie: Oh boy oh boy oh boy were you wrong.
开萝尔:那就是说,你做的是自己想要做的.
Carol: So you did what you wanted to do?
麦琪:我仍然是我.
Maggie: I still am.
开萝尔:你认为我也应该有自己的家庭么?
Carol: So you're saying I should have a family?
麦琪:不.
Maggie: No.
开萝尔:你认为我应该有自己的事业?
Carol: So, you're saying that I should have a career?
麦琪:不.
Maggie: No.
开萝尔:妈妈,我真的无所适从了.
Carol: Mum, I'm really getting confused here.
麦琪:好.因为这样一来,
Maggie: Good.Because that means that you are beginning to realize that
意味着你开始领会到你面临着选择.
you have options.
杰森:只要我们高兴,为什么不可以来点盖瑞的老歌呢?
Jason: Well, as long as we are set up, why not have some classic Gary Pucket?
迈克:性感么?
Mike: Hot?Was she hot?
她性感么?用一到十分来评判,
Let's just say that on a scale of one to ten,
她能得七点四七分?
she was a seven forty seven.
女孩1:我妈妈说,把那蓝罩衫拿回来,小姐.
Girl a: So my mum says; take that blue blouse back young lady.
女孩2:和我妈妈相比,你妈妈听起来好多了.我,好像,没有选择.好像是,她对自己的生活不满,所以她想指挥我的生活.
Girl b: Well your mother sounds great compared to my mother.I have, like, no choices.I mean it's like she's sick of her life, so she wants to lead mine.
开萝尔:我的母亲就不是那个样子.
Carol: My mother's not like that.
女孩1:你是在跟我们说话么?
Girl a: Are you talking to us?
开萝尔:是啊.我的母亲允许我自己作出选择,
Carol: Yeah.My mother lets me make my own choices.
她希望我能自己做出选择.
She wants me to make my own
她鼓励我做出自己的选择.这难道很难以置信么?
choices.She expects me to make my own choices.Isn't that incredible?
女孩2:你是书看的太多了.
Girl b: Too much studying.
开萝尔:错.看,
Carol: Wrong.See, it's all up to me.
一切都取决于我.我自己真的想把午餐的时间用于学习么?我自己真的想要那些压力么?
Do I really want to spend every lunch hour studying?
我自己真的想要跳级么?不,不,
Do I really want all the pressure?Do I really want to skip this grade?
不,我不想跳级.
No.No.No I do not want to skip this grade.
迈克:好!今儿是我走运的日子.
Mike: Alright!This is my day.
扩音器:迈克*希佛,迈克*希佛,
Loudspeaker: Mike Seaver.Mike Seaver I want you in my office in five minutes,
请你五分钟后来我办公室,这一次,千真万确.
and this time there is no mistake.
本:妈妈,妈妈,开萝尔刚放了你录的她出生时的磁带.
Ben: Mum, mum, Carol just played that tape you made when she was born.
麦琪:哦,再放一遍.
Maggie: Oh again.
本:好.我还不知道以前人家就发明了录音机.
Ben: Yeah.I didn't even know tape recorders were invented in the olden days.
杰森:哦,对.就在大火之后,我们才想到那个.
Jason: Oh yes.We came up with that right after fire.
本:什么时候我可以听听你们录的我出生时候的磁带呢?
Ben: Well, when do I get to hear the tape you made when I was born?
麦琪:你的磁带?
Maggie: Your tape?
杰森:呃------
Jason: Ummm.
麦琪:是这样的,本,好孩子.当,当你有第一个孩子的时候,你想记住每一个瞬间.而之后……
Maggie: You see Ben, old buddy.When, when first you have children, you want to capture every moment.And then..
杰森:我们是不是把你的磁带给放到另外一个箱子里了.我早上去找.
Jason: I think we packed yours in a different box.I'll get it in the morning.
本:好!
Ben: Alright!
麦琪:杰森,本出生的时候我们没录音啊.
Maggie: Jason, we didn't make a tape when Ben was born.
杰森:我们还没录呢.我们这就给他录.
Jason: Well, not yet we haven't.
麦琪:等会儿.什么意思?
杰森:你还记得怎么生孩子.一,二,三,用力!
00:23:02,200
Maggie: Wait a minute. Jason: You remember how it goes.One two three push!